Guide to the Nationalism and progress in free Asia conference tape recordings, 1955
Nationalism and progress in free Asia conference tape recordings, 1955
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Nationalism and progress in free Asia conference tape recordings, 1955
4521
Johns Hopkins University.School of Advanced International Studies.
27 cassettes.
Audiotapes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Audio tapes of seminars preceding the conference.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The School of Advanced International Studies at Johns Hopkins University sponsored a conference held in Washington, D.C., Aug. 1955 and Rangoon, Burma, Oct. 1955.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Audio tapes of seminars preceding the conference. Subjects include: "The Constitution and Organization of Government in Burma", "Problems of Local Government in Burma," Dr. Hugh Tinker; "Pre-Buddhist Influences on Burmese Buddhism," "The Cultural Aspects of Burmese Life," Dr. Htin Aung; "History of Nationalism in Burma", "The Evolution of Political Parties in Burma," Dr. Kyaw Thet; "The Essentials of Buddhist Doctrine," U Aung Than; "Agricultural Development in Burma," Dr. Takahashi; "The Industrial Development of Burma," U Aye Hlaing; "Democratic Administration in Burma," "Geography of Burma as it Related to Human History," Daw Thin Kyi; "Burma's Relations with the Western Nations," U Ohn Gaing; "Survey of the Languages of Burma," G. H. Luce; and "Nationalism in Indonesia," Soe Bagio.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Johns Hopkins University.; Aung Than,; Aye Hlaing,; Bagio, Soe.; Daw Thin Kyi.; Furnivall, J. S. (John Sydenham); Htin Aung.; Kyo` Sak`.; Luce, G. H. (Gordon Hannington), 1889-1979.; Ohn Gaing,; Tinker, Hugh.
Subjects:
Buddhism--Burma; Nationalism--Burma.; Nationalism--Indonesia.; Agricultural development projects--Burma.; Industries--Burma.
Places:
Burma--Politics and government.; Burma--Foreign relations.; Burma--Languages.; Burma--History.; Burma--Economic conditions.; Indonesia--History.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Dr. Hugh Tinker, The Constitution and Organization of Government in Burma., Dec. 11, 1954; 1A (Box 1)
- Dr. Htin Aung, Pre-Buddhist Influences on Burmese Buddhism, Nov. 17, 1954; 1B (Box 1)
- Dr. Htin Aung, Pre-Buddhist Influences on Burmese Buddhism (cont.), Nov. 19, 1954; 2A (Box 1)
- Dr. Kyaw Thet, History of Nationalism in Burma, Nov. 19, 1954; 2A (Box 1)
- Dr. Kyaw Thet, History of Nationalism in Burma, Nov. 19, 1954; 2B (Box 1)
- Dr. Kyaw Thet, The Evolution of Political Parties in Burma, Nov. 24, 1954; 3A (Box 1)
- Dr. Kyaw Thet, The Evolution of Political Parties in Burma (cont.), Nov. 24, 1954; 3B (Box 1)
- U Aung Than, The Essentials of Buddhist Doctrine, Nov. 26, 1954; 4A (Box 1)
- U Aung Than, The Essentials of Buddhist Doctrine (cont.), Nov. 26, 1954; 4B (Box 1)
- Dr. Htin Aung, The Cultural Aspects of Burmese Life, Dec. 2, 1954; 6A (Box 1)
- Dr. Htin Aung, The Cultural Aspects of Burmese Life, Dec. 2, 1954; 6B (Box 1)
- Dr. Hugh Tinker, Problems of Local Government in Burma, Dec. 12, 1954; 7A (Box 1)
- Dr. Hugh Tinker, Problems of Local Government in Burma, Dec. 12, 1954; 7B (Box 1)
- Dr. Takahashi, Agricultural Development in Burma, Dec. 17, 1954; 8A (Box 1)
- Dr. Takahashi, Agricultural Development in Burma, Dec. 17, 1954; 8B (Box 1)
- U Aye Hlaing, The Industrial Development of Burma, Dec. 22, 1954; 9A (Box 1)
- U Aye Hlaing, The Industrial Development of Burma, Dec. 22, 1954; 9B (Box 1)
- J.S. Furnivall, Democratic Administration in Burma, Jan. 7, 1954; 10A (Box 1)
- J.S. Furnivall, Democratic Administration in Burma, Jan. 7, 1954; 10B (Box 1)
- Daw Thin Kyi, Geography of Burma as it related to Human History, Jan. 14, 1954; 11A (Box 1)
- Daw Thin Kyi, Geography of Burma as it related to Human History, Jan. 14, 1954; 11B (Box 1)
- U Ohn Gaing, Burma's Relations with the Western Nations, Jan. 21, 1955; 12A (Box 1)
- U Ohn Gaing, Burma's Relations with the Western Nations, Jan. 21, 1955; 12B (Box 1)
- G.H. Luce, Survey of the Languages of Burma, Jan. 1, 1955; 13A (Box 1)
- G.H. Luce, Survey of the Languages of Burma, Jan. 1, 1955; 13B (Box 1)
- Soe Bagio, Nationalism in Indonesia, Feb. 2, 1955; 14A (Box 1)
- Soe Bagio, Nationalism in Indonesia, Feb. 2, 1955; 14B (Box 1)